Guide to the Brian Kiss Photographs of Stained Glass in The Sterling Memorial Library Nave, Yale University
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Brian Kiss photographs of stained glass in the Sterling Memorial Library Nave, Yale University
2014
RU 1136
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1360
The collection consists of eighty .tiff files of close-up digital images of the stained glass medallion windows located in the Sterling Memorial Library Nave.
Kiss, Brian
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The photographs for this collection were donated by Brian Kiss, 2014.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of eighty .tiff files of close-up digital images of the stained glass medallion windows located in the Sterling Memorial Library Nave.
Biographical / Historical
Originally from Shelton, Connecticut, Brian Kiss has been an employee of Sterling Memorial Library since 2006. His interest in photography began in high school and has focused on music and fashion photography. Following the opening of the Front Line Services Desk in the Nave in 2014, Brian grew enamored of the stained glass created by G. Owen Bonawit in the 1930s and lent his photographic skills to capturing the beauty of these newly restored pieces of art.
The eighty donated images are a collection of his favorite works, shot close up to capture the detail of each piece. His favorite, "Monumental Gratitude" depicts a boat being tossed on stormy waters.
Arrangement
The material is arranged as received from the donor.
Academic libraries; Glass paintings and stainings; Photography; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Kiss, Brian
- Inventory [computer files], Accession 2015-A-033 (Reel 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
  - Branford Stockade, 1
  - Connecticut Troops in Boston, 1
  - Granting the Charter, 1
  - Killingworth Meeting House, 1
  - Phantom Ship, 1
  - Russel House, Branford, 1
  - Taking the College Corn (To Cambridge), 1
  - The Ministers Arriving at the Russel House in 1701, 1
  - Dummer's Ship Unloading, 1
  - Elihu Yale from the Elihu Yale Snuff Box in the Library, 1
  - Jeremiah Dummer, 1
  - Saybrook, Connecticut, 1
  - Sir Isaac Newton Turning to His Bookshelves to Select Books, 1
  - Sir John Davie Receiving Word of His Succession to the Title, 1
  - Sir Richard Blackmore Riding up in his Chariot in London, 1
  - Yale's House at Wrexham, 1
  - Black Horse Tavern, 1
  - Collegiate School at Saybrook, 1
  - Hector entering New Haven Harbor, 1
  - Lord House at Saybrook, 1
  - Miles's Tavern, New Haven, 1
  - New Haven Marketplace, 1
  - Old New Haven Wharves, 1
  - Ox Carts Fording the Stream, Bringing Books to New Haven, 1
  - Banquet in the Library, First Commencement, 1
  - Building the College House, 1
  - Cutler and the Trustees, 1
  - President's House, 1722, 1
  - Processing to the Meeting House, First Commencement, 1
  - Second Meeting House, New Haven, 1
  - The Gallant Colonel and the Ladies, First Commencement, 1
  - Undergraduate of 1720, 1
  - Berkeley Family Portrait (from Kingsley's Yale College ), 1
  - Berkeley's Home in Rhode Island (from Kingsley's Yale College ), 1
  - Buck's View of Yale College, 1
  - Friendly Argument in the Library, 1723, 1
  - Laying out the College Fans at Litchfield, 1739, 1
  - Student Roughhousing, 1738, 1
  - Students Auctioning Off Food in Commons, 1752, 1
  - "Monumental Gratitude", 1
  - Connecticut Hall (From Kingsley's Yale College ), 1
  - Freshmen Clearing the Snow from the College Yard, 1
  - Inspection of a Student's Room by the Scholar, 1
  - Interior of the Library, 1717, 1
  - Presentation Day, 1751, 1
  - Public Reception to Benjamin Franklin, Stiles Delivering a Latin Lecture, 1
  - Stiles's View of the College, 1
  - Student Caught in the Act of Ringing, 1
  - Commencement, 1760; a Humble Confession in the Meeting House, 1
  - The Earl of Loundon Visits New Haven, 1
  - Five Sophomores and a Freshman Steal Eight Hens From a Widow, 1
  - Hale's School at New London, 1
  - James Hillhouse Planting the Trees on Hillhouse Avenue, 1
  - Linonia Play: Beaux Stratagem, 1
  - Nathan Hale, Hillhouse, etc. Giving the First Books to Linonia, 1769, 1
  - Powder Horn View of the College, 1
  - Bowen's Yale College, 1786, 1
  - Demanding the Keys to the Powder House, 1
  - Nathan Hale's Execution (from the Book of the Yale Pageant ), 1
  - President Daggett, With His Musket, Going Out to Defend The Town, 1
  - Privateer Satisfaction, 1
  - Removing the Books from the Library for Safety, 1
  - Soldier of the Revolution (from the Brooks Bookplate), 1
  - Washington Passes Through New Haven, 1
  - Camp Putnam, 1832 ( from the Book of the Yale Pageant ), 1
  - Doolittle's View of the Green, 1807, 1
  - Going to Chapel, 1824, 1
  - Jocelyn View of Yale College, 1822, 1
  - Moral Library, 1828 (from the Bookplate), 1
  - Old Library, 1842, 1
  - Society of the Cincinnati emblem from Trumbull's Insignia, 1
  - Soldier of 1812 (from the Brooks Bookplate), 1
  - Burial of Euclid, 1
  - Elizabethan Club (founded in 1911), 1
  - Examination in Alumni Hall, 1
  - Initiation, 1867, 1
  - Junior Exhibition (from the Program of 1842 ), 1
  - Linsly Hall, 1
  - Yale Fence (from Kingsley's Yale College ), 1
  - Yale Pageant-Wedding (from the color photograph), 1